mikeholt.com 2015-06-09

# Mike Holt Privacy Policy

You are in control of the information you provide to MikeHolt.com

Because protecting your privacy is important to us, we want you to know that we respect and will continue to respect and protect the information you provide to MikeHolt.com. This notice discloses our Privacy Policy; by visiting MikeHolt.com you accept these terms and conditions.  

  * What personal information is being gathered and how the information is used
  * Who the information will be shared with (if anyone)
  * Access to your information (including how to update or correct inaccuracies)
  * Safeguards in place to protect your information
  * Other information about your privacy

What personal information is being gathered by MikeHolt.com and how is this information being used?

**Member Registration**  
When you join a MikeHolt.com member area or service such as the Code Forum or free Newsletter subscription, you provide your name, email address, a unique login name, password, and password validation. 

This information is collected on the registration form for several reasons including: (i) personal identification; (ii) to allow us to contact you for customer service, if necessary; (iii) to customize the content of our site to meet your specific needs; and (iv) to send you an email regarding Mike Holt's safety or industry messages.

**Newsletters and Forums**  
MikeHolt.com Newsletters and Code Forums are optional benefits for members that keep you up to date with the latest Code news and to allow you to obtain answers to your Code questions online. However, you may always decline to receive these email messages.

**Online Surveys**  
MikeHolt.com values opinions, feedback and comments from members, so we frequently conduct online surveys. These surveys are entirely optional for all members. Typically, the information is aggregated and used to make improvements to MikeHolt.com and to develop content, features and promotions for members, and to improve our products and services. Survey participants are anonymous unless otherwise stated in the survey. By checking the appropriate box, you may leave your comments and feedback for our review without fear that they will be shared or publicized.

**Cookies**  
"Cookies" are small pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive. MikeHolt.com uses cookies to allow you to login without having to type your login name each time. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but if you prefer, you can edit your browser options to block them in the future.

Who will the information be shared with, if anyone?  
We do not sell individual customer names or other private profile information to third parties and have no intention of doing so in the future. 

See "What other information should I know about my privacy? " below. 

How can you access, opt out, or update your information?  
At any time, you can view and/or update your MikeHolt.com newsletter subscriptions or your Code Forum profile as follows:

  * To edit your code forum profile: [click here](http://forums.mikeholt.com/usercp.php).
  * To edit your newsletter subscription options, click here and follow the instructions displayed

What safeguards are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of your information?  
All personally identifiable information you provide to MikeHolt.com is transmitted using SSL (Secure Socket Layer) encryption. SSL is a proven coding system that lets your browser automatically encrypt, or scramble, data before you send it to us. In addition, when you make purchases on MikeHolt.com, you are protected by MikeHolt.com's Shop Safe Guarantee.

What other information should I know about my privacy?  
MikeHolt.com contains links to other Web sites. Please note that when you click on one of these links, you are entering another Web site for which MikeHolt.com has no responsibility. We encourage you to read the privacy statements of all such sites as their policies may be materially different from MikeHolt.com's Privacy Statement. Of course, you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords and any account information. Please be very careful, responsible, and alert with this information, especially whenever you're online. 

In addition to the circumstances described above, MikeHolt.com may disclose member information if required to do so by law, court order, as requested by other government or law enforcement authority, or in the good faith belief that disclosure is otherwise necessary or advisable including, without limitation, to protect the rights or properties of MikeHolt.com or when we have reason to believe that disclosing the information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing interference with our rights or properties, whether intentionally or otherwise, or when anyone else could be harmed by such activities.

Any material changes in the way MikeHolt.com uses personal information will be described in future versions of this Privacy Statement. Of course, you may always submit concerns regarding our Privacy Statement or our privacy practices to [mike@mikeholt.com](mailto:mike@mikeholt.com). Please reference the privacy policy in your subject line. MikeHolt.com will attempt to respond to all reasonable concerns or inquiries within five business days of receipt.
